giro.com 2010-05-08

# Giro / Privacy Policy

Below is a simplified description of a new law on website privacy (the Online Privacy Protection Act of 2003) for anyone with a website visited by people living in California, and on which website collects info on those who visit that site.

While most of our websites don't likely collect info directly from consumers (via cookies and such), they do suggest consumers e-mail us, and with those e-mails we do collect information. Therefore. we need to add a "privacy policy" in the main menu of each of our websites.

The new law applies to all "operators" of commercial websites and online services that collect personally identifiable information about California consumers. This includes out-of-state operators as well as those based in California.

The term "operator" means the owner of a website or an online service. It does not include third parties that may operate, host or manage the site or service or who process information on behalf of the owner. The term "personally identifiable information" means individually identifiable information collected online about individual consumers, such as a first and last name, a street address, an e-mail address, a telephone number, a social security number or any other identifier that would permit the operator, or others who obtain access to that information, to contact a specific individual. The term "consumer" means any individual who seeks or acquires goods, services, money or credit for personal, family or household purposes. OPPA does not apply to owners of websites that only collect information about other businesses.

The new law requires an operator to conspicuously post a privacy policy on its website or in the case of an online service, to use reasonable means to make that policy available to consumers. In order to meet the "conspicuously posted" requirement:

  * The privacy policy must appear prominently on the home page of a website;
  * The privacy policy must be directly linked to the home page by means of an icon that contains the word "privacy" and uses a color that contrasts with the background of the web page; or 
  * The privacy policy must be linked to the home page by means of a hypertext link that includes the word "privacy," is written in capital letters equal to or greater in size than the surrounding text, or is otherwise readily distinguishable from the surrounding text on the home page.

_The privacy policy itself must do all of the following:_

  * It must identify the categories of personally identifiable information that the operator collects;
  * It must identify the categories of third parties with whom the operator may share the personally identifiable information that it collects;
  * It must describe the process (if any) by which consumers can review and request changes to any of the collected information;
  * It must describe the process by which the operator will notify consumers of material changes in its privacy policy; and
  * It must identify the effective date of the privacy policy.

OPPA contains a built-in "cure period"-it expressly provides that an operator who has been notified that it is not complying with the requirement to post its privacy policy will not be considered in violation of the law unless it fails to post its privacy policy within 30 days of such notification. Other provisions of the new law indicate that an operator intentionally failing to comply with the law will be considered in violation of OPPA even if the noncompliance is immaterial, while an operator whose noncompliance is not intentional, but negligent, will only be considered in violation of OPPA if the noncompliance is material.

The new law does not itself contain enforcement provisions. It is expected that OPPA will be enforced through California's Unfair Competition Law (the "UCL"), which is located at Business and Professions Code §§17200-17209.

Under the UCL, the Attorney General, district attorneys, and certain city and county attorneys may bring civil actions based on acts of "unfair competition" as defined in Business and Professions Code § 17200. Acts of "unfair competition" include acts, in business, that violate any law, which means that once OPPA takes effect in July 2004, a violation of OPPA will also be a violation of the UCL. The identified law enforcement officials may seek civil penalties and injunctive or other equitable relief.

Of greater concern, under the UCL "any person" may bring an action "in the interests of itself, its members, or the general public." This "private attorney general" provision has been broadly interpreted to allow a person with no personal interest and who has suffered no harm to bring a private action for restitution (to be paid to those who have suffered harm) or injunctive relief. 2 In a private attorney general action brought under this special standing provision, the plaintiff may also recover attorney's fees. Therefore, private plaintiffs will be able to use alleged violations of OPPA as a basis for asserting private UCL claims.

Companies must begin complying with the new law immediately. All website privacy policies should disclose:

  * What information website operators collect from those visiting their sites;
  * How that information is used;
  * With whom it is shared;
  * How consumers can review and correct the collected information;
  * Whether consumers can "opt out" of having that information retained by the operator or shared with others; and
  * How consumers can communicate with the operator.

  1. Other examples include a new law requiring companies to maintain databases that include personal information about California residents to disclose any breach in security of those databases, which became effective on July 1, 2003; and a broad prohibition against sending unsolicited commercial e-mail messages ("spam") to California e-mail addresses, which became effective January 1, 2004.

Giro, a division of Bell Sports, Inc. ("Bell Sports, Inc.", "we" or "us"), understands that using the internet, downloading files and making purchases online involves a great deal of trust on your part. We take that trust seriously, which is why we seek to ensure the security and confidentiality of your personal information online. This privacy policy is an effort to answer any privacy-related questions you may have. If you have questions that are not addressed here, please submit them to us by sending an email to [webmaster@giro.com](mailto:webmaster@giro.com).

The purpose of this privacy policy (the "Policy") is to help you understand what kinds of personally identifiable information we may gather about you when you visit the Bell Sports, Inc. web site located at www.giro.com and related sub-domains (the "Site"), how we may use that information, whether we will disclose it, and how you can correct or update it. We note that this Policy sets forth our online information collection and use policies under U.S. law. We also note that we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children (that is, minors younger than thirteen years of age).

If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, you should not use the Site. We reserve the right to update or modify this Policy from time to time, and such changes to the Policy will be effective immediately; therefore please bookmark this page and review it periodically to assure familiarity with the most current version of the Policy. You can tell if the Policy has been updated since you last reviewed it by checking the "Last Revised" date at the beginning of the Policy.

This Policy is the sole authorized statement of Bell Sports, Inc.'s practices with respect to the online collection of personally identifiable information and the usage of such information. Any summaries of this Policy generated by third party software or otherwise (for example, in connection with the "Platform for Privacy Preferences" or "P3P") shall have no legal effect, are in no way binding upon Bell Sports, Inc., shall not be relied upon in substitute for this Policy, and neither supersede nor modify this Policy.

To assist you with your review of our Policy, we have provided answers to questions that you may find important:

  * What Personal Information We Collect
  * How We Use the Personal Information We Collect
  * Marketing Communications: Opting Out
  * Cookies
  * Web Beacons
  * How We Protect Your Personal Information
  * Correcting/Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences
  * Other Information We Collect
  * Advertisers
  * Sweepstakes and Promotions
  * Co-branded Sites: Links to Other Sites
  * Online vs. Offlince Practices
  * Contacting Bell Sports, Inc.

Bell Sports, Inc. collects personally identifiable information that you specifically and voluntarily provide on the Site or by email to Bell Sports, Inc. Personally identifiable information is information that identifies you as a specific individual; for example: your name, company name, account number, physical or email address, and phone number plus other information that personally identifies you including your industry, the number of employees at your company and purchase history. The Site may include both public areas, open to all visitors, and private areas that are open only to those visitors who choose to register. In addition, visitors can sign up on the Site to request email newsletters and other information from Bell Sports, Inc.

Bell Sports, Inc. collects personally identifiable information from you when you:

  * Make a purchase
  * Create an account
  * Contact a phone sales representative
  * Are contacted by a phone sales representative
  * Subscribe to our newsletter
  * Request a catalog
  * Participate in a survey
  * Register at our website

We use the personally identifiable information that you provide to us in order to 1) fulfill requests for products, services and/or information, 2) provide customer service, 3) offer new products or services, 4) measure and improve the effectiveness of our Site and our marketing endeavors, 5) tailor our online offerings to your preferences, 6) administer promotions or surveys, and 7) achieve other business purposes as permitted under applicable law.

When you make a purchase on our Site we collect credit card information including card number, card type, cardholder name and billing address and expiration date in order to bill you for purchases made through Bell Sports, Inc. Please review our Credit Card Policy for additional information.

Bell Sports, Inc. may disclose personally identifiable information to consultants, professional advisors and contractors who perform services on our behalf, but only to the extent necessary for them to perform such services. At times, Bell Sports, Inc. may seek to validate the personally identifiable information we have collected via an audit by a third party designed to determine the accuracy of and/or to update the information collected. We may also combine data that we collect online with data collected offline (such as through purchases made through one of our catalogs), or with data provided by other parties.

Bell Sports, Inc. shares personally identifiable information collected from our visitors and customers with our affiliated or related companies, including its parent company, affiliates, subsidiaries or its parent company's other subsidiaries.

Bell Sports, Inc. reserves the right to release personally identifiable information concerning any visitor when that visitor is believed by Bell Sports, Inc. to be in violation of any published guidelines for the use of the Site, or participates (or is suspected of participating) in any illegal or potentially illegal activity. Bell Sports, Inc. also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information to comply with applicable law, in response to civil subpoenas or discovery requests, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is required to protect the rights, property, safety or security of Bell Sports, Inc., our visitors or the public, or to respond to an emergency.

In the event that we sell or otherwise transfer to a third party assets related either (a) to the Site or (b) to one or more of our businesses, divisions or affiliated companies, we reserve the right to also transfer any and all information (including any personally identifiable information) associated with the Site and/or any business, division or affiliated company to such third party. However, all personally identifiable information transferred to such third party shall be transferred subject to the usage restrictions contained in Bell Sports, Inc.'s privacy policy. Please note that we are not responsible for retracting your personally identifiable information from any third parties with whom we have shared your information pursuant to the terms of this Policy.

When you provide personally identifiable information to us, including when registering to receive email newsletters, catalog subscriptions or other information, or to make a purchase, Bell Sports, Inc. provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of having your information used for marketing communications. Unless you have opted out of receiving such communications, Bell Sports, Inc. may use your personally identifiable information to forward you, via email or mail, advertisements concerning Bell Sports, Inc. products, services, special promotions, surveys or other opportunities from Bell Sports, Inc. that we think may be of interest to you. Such email advertisements may also concern third party companies' products and services, including companies in industries such as hardware and software, and other providers of the types of products that are sold or featured on the Site.

Bell Sports, Inc. has partnered with third parties to offer our customers and Site visitors a variety of products and services. Other than as set forth herein, we will not sell or lease your email address to third party advertisers to solicit you directly. However Bell Sports, Inc. may share personally identifiable information (such as your physical mailing address - but not your email address) with our marketing partners in order for them to offer you additional products and services that Bell Sports, Inc. believes may be of interest to you. Although we only work with third parties whom we believe to be reputable, our marketing partners may have different privacy policies and practices than Bell Sports, Inc. We encourage you to review our marketing partners' privacy policies to further understand their procedures for collecting, using and disclosing your information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of our marketing partners or any other third parties. If you decide that you would like to discontinue receiving promotional materials from these or any third parties, please contact them directly.

Should you wish to change your preferences regarding the information that you receive from Bell Sports, Inc. or its affiliates, or would prefer that we not share personally identifiable information with our marketing partners, please refer to the paragraph below entitled "Correcting/Updating Your Personal Information and Preferences" Please note that we are not responsible for retracting your personally identifiable information from any third parties with whom we have shared your information pursuant to the terms and conditions of this Policy.

Upon visiting our Site we will assign you a unique ID in the form of a "cookie". A cookie is a piece of information that our server places on your computer's hard drive, which Bell Sports, Inc. may associate with your personally identifiable information when you log on to the site. Cookies are used for such purposes as facilitating and personalizing your shopping and ordering experience, keeping track of your shopping basket during your visit, helping diagnose problems with our server, and administering our Site. We may use the information collected through cookies for marketing purposes to inform you of special offers, better understand your needs or answer your questions. For more information about cookies, please see our Cookie FAQs. NOTE: You can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your web browser, and you may remove them from your computer at any time at your discretion.

Some Bell Sports, Inc. Web pages and HTML-formatted email newsletters may use Web beacons to compile aggregate statistics about website usage. A Web beacon is an electronic image, often called a single-pixel (1x1) or clear GIF that is ordinarily not visible to the site visitor. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a visitor's computer, such as a visitor's cookie number, time and date of a page or image view, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. When used in an email, they can tell us whether an email has been opened.

To help ensure the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, Bell Sports, Inc. seeks to use security technology and procedures, which are reviewed periodically. We use encryption technology and Secure Socket Layers ("SSL") in all areas where personal and account information is required. This means that the personal information you submit to us via our Site is encrypted by your computer, and then decrypted again on our side, discouraging others from accessing your private information during transmission. If your browser does not support SSL, or if you are unable to establish a secure connection due to a company firewall, please call us at 469-417-6765 to place your order by phone.

In addition, your personal, account information, and transaction history are kept behind our firewall.

If you would like to have your personally identifiable information removed from Bell Sports, Inc.'s databases, or to make changes to your personally identifiable information or to your preferences regarding the use of your personally identifiable information for marketing purposes, please click here. We will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request. Please note that we may need to contact you in order to be sure that we are updating the appropriate information. When requesting that personally identifiable information be updated or that your preferences be changed, please keep in mind that until the change is implemented, you may still receive email and/or physical mailings from us. Furthermore, there will be residual information that will remain within Bell Sports, Inc. databases, access logs and other records, which may contain such personally identifiable information. The residual information will not be used for commercial purposes; however, Bell Sports, Inc. reserves the right, from time to time, to contact former customers or visitors to the Site. Please note that we are not responsible for retracting your personally identifiable information from third parties with whom we have shared your information pursuant to the terms and conditions of this Policy.

Information About Your Computer and Your Site Activities: When a visitor comes to our Site we collect and aggregate information about the visitor's computer (such as its IP address, operating system and browser software), and click-stream information (such as the address (or "URL") of the Web site that the visitor came from before visiting our Site, which pages of the Site were visited, the order in which they were visited and which hyperlinks were clicked) for the purpose of assessing our Site traffic and the effectiveness of our Site content, as well as to help diagnose problems with our servers. This data allows us to improve the quality of your visit by streamlining your ability to navigate the Site, and to develop featured programs and content that will be of interest to our customers and Site visitors.

Aggregated Information: Bell Sports, Inc. may collect and aggregate demographic information about our Site visitors. For example, we may seek to aggregate information regarding the gender make up, average age and range of income levels of Site visitors in order to better service our user community. We may use such information in its aggregated form without restriction.

Information About Corporate and Other Organizational Customers: We may collect information pertaining solely to corporations, governmental or educational entities, or other business or not-for-profit entities, such as, for example, a company's address. We may use any such corporate information without restriction. In an effort to better support our customers by delivering more relevant marketing communications, Bell Sports, Inc. will, on occasion, purchase third party information about businesses and other entities that are our customers. The company information we purchase may include number of employees, or annual sales volume and company structure. This is used to customize such customers' online/offline experience and to supplement our internal sales information to better serve you.

Bell Sports, Inc. may use outside advertising companies ("Advertisers") to serve advertisements on the Site. Please be advised that such Advertisers may use cookies or other technologies to enable such Advertisers to record which ads your browser has seen, and which Site pages you may have been viewing when the ads were delivered.

We may from time to time offer sweepstakes, contests or other similar promotions on the Site. Additional personally identifiable information may be required in order to participate in such promotions, so that we may, for example, verify entrants' eligibility and identity and notify winners. Participation in such promotions is completely voluntary. If and when we sponsor such promotions, we will post relevant privacy information in the respective "official rules" and/or registration areas for such promotions. That privacy information, to the extent it conflicts with this Policy, will govern that particular sweepstakes, contest or promotion-please remember to read it carefully.

Other companies may offer sweepstakes, contests or similar promotions through our Site, including through the Rebates & Coupons page. Bell Sports, Inc. is not responsible for any such promotions offered by third parties. Please read all related terms and conditions carefully, or contact the applicable third party for more information. The collection and use of personal information in connection with such promotions is governed by such third party's privacy policy, and not by the policies of Bell Sports, Inc.

The Site offers certain features that are provided and/or hosted by third parties, but that may be presented on pages displaying Bell Sports, Inc.'s branding. For example, Bell Sports, Inc.-branded pages featuring investor relations information about Bell Sports, Inc. may be created and operated by a third party data provider specializing in such information. The Site may also contain links to other Web sites, or other affiliated sites (e.g., event sponsors, or companies offering rebates or other promotions through our Rebates & Coupons page). We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any such Web sites, including such sites' use of any information (such as IP number, browser type or operating system) collected when visitors to the Site click through links to those sites. Even though such information might not identify you personally, we strongly encourage you to become familiar with the privacy practices of any third party sites.

Please note that this Policy applies solely to our online information-gathering and dissemination practices in connection with the Site, and does not apply to any of our practices conducted offline other than as expressly set forth in this Policy.

Should you have any questions, please email us at [webmaster@giro.com](mailto:webmaster@giro.com). 

GIRO is sensitive to privacy issues on the Internet. We believe that it is important you know how we treat the information about you that we receive via the Site.

In general, you may visit the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personally identifiable information about you. Our servers capture, but do not collect, the IP addresses, domain names and network identifiers of our users. This information is aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the Site, pages viewed, etc. GIRO uses this information to measure the use of our Site and to improve the content of our Site. E-mail addresses and other personally identifiable information such as first and last name, home or other physical address, telephone number and other similar information are known only when voluntarily provided by a visitor for registration for sweepstakes, contests, promotions or other participation of visitors in any available online interactive activities.

Unless otherwise disclosed during the collection, personally identifiable information that may be collected in connection with visitors to this Site is retained by GIRO or it’s parent corporations ("Affiliates"). GIRO and our Affiliates do not sell, transfer or otherwise disclose this personally identifiable information outside those companies, except where disclosure is required by law.

We may use the personal information you provide for any of the following purposes: (1) to understand the use of our Site and make improvements; (2) to fulfill prizes; (3) to respond to specific requests from visitors; (4) to obtain parental consent from visitors under 18 years of age, where necessary; (5) to provide any necessary notices to our visitors or their parent or guardians, where necessary; (6) to protect the security or integrity of our Site when necessary; (7) to send you notices and solicitations regarding Site and our businesses; and (8) in general to promote and market our products to you. These solicitations may take the form of mailings via U.S. mail or other couriers, telephone calls, e-mail solicitations and other methods of contact. If you do not want to receive these solicitations from us using your personally identifiable information, you may specify this during registration, or you may notify us by contacting Giro, c/o Webmaster, 380 Encinal Street, Santa Cruz, CA 95060.

It is our policy that visitors to our Site who are under the age of 18 should not post on or provide information to our Site without the consent of their parents. You should supervise the online activities of your children, and consider the use of parental control tools available from online services and software providers that help provide a kid-friendly Internet environment.

A technology called "cookies" may be used to provide you with tailored information. A "cookie" is a tiny element of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your hard drive so we can recognize you when you return. You may be able to set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. Our cookies collect the operating system and browser that a visitor is using.

This Site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control.

This Site may contain links to other sites of third parties. We are not responsible for the content of privacy practices of those other sites.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. You are responsible for checking this policy when you visit our Site to review the current policy. If you do not agree with the policy, you should cease use of the Site immediately.
